<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en, tr"><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="4.3.3">Jekyll</generator><link href="https://efe-atas.github.io/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml"/><link href="https://efe-atas.github.io/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" hreflang="en, tr"/><updated>2025-09-01T15:07:51+00:00</updated><id>https://efe-atas.github.io/feed.xml</id><title type="html">blank</title><subtitle>Computer Science Student</subtitle><entry><title type="html">my summer 2025</title><link href="https://efe-atas.github.io/blog/2025/intern/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="my summer 2025"/><published>2025-09-01T12:45:00+00:00</published><updated>2025-09-01T12:45:00+00:00</updated><id>https://efe-atas.github.io/blog/2025/intern</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://efe-atas.github.io/blog/2025/intern/"><![CDATA[<p>I talked about my summer goals</p> <p>Let’s talk about what happened</p> <ul> <li>yes, I found a very good internship</li> <li>4 LeetCode questions :/</li> <li>one day or day one :/</li> <li>I gave up learning any framework, I focused on learning theory</li> <li>my English skills are still at the same level</li> <li>smile 3 times a day (yes, I did it)</li> <li>I had never thought about going abroad this summer but I went to Germany for 5 days, it was excellent</li> <li>I also went on a very beautiful holiday</li> </ul> <h1 id="what-happened-in-my-internship">What happened in my internship</h1> <p>ChatGPT is killing my writing skills. I am too lazy to tell my internship adventure. But let me try.<br/> This was my first big company internship. One of the biggest software companies in Turkey. I worked in the Big Data and AI team for 30 workdays.<br/> At first, I was really annoyed by the procedures of a big company. I had to wait for my laptop for 4 days. I was used to being fast at work in my previous company (a start-up).<br/> I forgot to tell you, they gave us a thermos, hat, and bag. I really liked the thermos and I’m still using it btw. The first week of the internship did not feel good to me. But later weeks we took the case and researched it.<br/> It was an audio classification problem. At first, I thought it was a simple problem. But the domain of the problem was really problematic. We needed to do a lot of work: researching methods, data scraping, data cleaning, model-driven development, later data-driven development, and we also created an end-to-end full stack app for the user who would use it later. There are also plenty of other things but I cannot explain them due to my contract.</p> <h1 id="what-happened-in-germany---not-ai-generated-emoji-i-put-it-here">What happened in Germany 🇩🇪 (not ai generated emoji i put it here)</h1> <p>My friend called me and said let’s go to Germany and I said yes, so we bought the tickets and went to Germany. Yes, it happened like that. I don’t want to explain a lot of things about my journey but I want to share my observations:</p> <ul> <li>KEBAP DONER IN ANKARA (TURKEY) IS FAR FAR BETTER THAN IN GERMANY. BUT THE PORTION OF DONER IN GERMANY IS NEARLY THREE TIMES MORE THAN IN TURKEY.</li> <li>Most people obey the rules willingly.</li> <li>Churches everywhere like in other EU countries.</li> <li>I ate my first FIVE GUYS, a huge delicious burger. I wrote a note on a table in Munich Five Guys, I hope you will see it.</li> <li>Public transportation is okay.</li> <li>YES, CARS ARE CHEAPER and I saw a lot of luxury cars on the road.</li> <li>In urinals there is no separator. That was my culture shock.</li> <li>I ate the best ice cream I have ever eaten.</li> <li>Turkish Kiraathane in Germany feels like a casino.</li> <li>NATURE is great. Everywhere is green and peaceful. I was thinking Germany was a grey country.</li> <li>Fun culture is great. I went to a concert in Augsburg, it was very fun. People are very nice.</li> <li>I used ChatGPT a lot during this trip, it helped me a lot.</li> </ul> <p>Maybe I forgot to mention something about my travel but I think this is enough for now.</p> <div class="row justify-content-sm-center"> <div class="col-sm-8 mt-3 mt-md-0"> <figure> <picture> <source class="responsive-img-srcset" srcset="/assets/img/IMG_7521-480.webp 480w,/assets/img/IMG_7521-800.webp 800w,/assets/img/IMG_7521-1400.webp 1400w," sizes="95vw" type="image/webp"/> <img src="/assets/img/IMG_7521.jpeg" class="img-fluid rounded z-depth-1" width="100%" height="auto" title="Nuremberg,Germany" loading="lazy" onerror="this.onerror=null; $('.responsive-img-srcset').remove();"/> </picture> </figure> </div> </div>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="thoughts-💭"/><summary type="html"><![CDATA[my summer]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">do not lose your faith</title><link href="https://efe-atas.github.io/blog/2025/donotloosefaith/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="do not lose your faith"/><published>2025-04-02T12:45:00+00:00</published><updated>2025-04-02T12:45:00+00:00</updated><id>https://efe-atas.github.io/blog/2025/donotloosefaith</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://efe-atas.github.io/blog/2025/donotloosefaith/"><![CDATA[<p>Its really hard times for being cs student nowadays. Everything changes faster than other areas. We need to unbelievable adaptation skills more than ever. We need to do not lose our faith. The worst thing could happen a person to lose their faith what he/she really wants to.</p> <p>For now, I feel a lot. I feel like missed all oppurtunities. But I told myself this sentence yesterday “If I can not accept my missing,may be i miss my future winnings”. Worst sentence ever btw. :D</p> <p>My words could seem written by crazy linkedin influencers but believe me i write this sentences from my heart and a little bit from my mind. Do not lose your faith. Even if the worst scenario there must be a path for us. I hope there will. I like what I doing and other things happen to me do not change this. Living in a 3rd world country (lack of merit, lack of justice) do not influence your faith. If I create value, there must be receiver in somewhere. Maybe it will be not in my greatest country but somewhere else.</p> <p>The long and the short of it believe in yourself, do not affect from outside world. Create valuable things, push yourself to limits.</p> <p>(I DO NOT ACT LIKE A TEACHER. I am also suffer from same issues as you like. I also recommend all of them to myself)</p> <div class="row justify-content-sm-center"> <div class="col-sm-8 mt-3 mt-md-0"> <figure> <picture> <source class="responsive-img-srcset" srcset="/assets/img/believe-480.webp 480w,/assets/img/believe-800.webp 800w,/assets/img/believe-1400.webp 1400w," sizes="95vw" type="image/webp"/> <img src="/assets/img/believe.png" class="img-fluid rounded z-depth-1" width="100%" height="auto" title="example image" loading="lazy" onerror="this.onerror=null; $('.responsive-img-srcset').remove();"/> </picture> </figure> </div> </div>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="thoughts-💭"/><summary type="html"><![CDATA[go brrrrrr]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">my crazy faking roadmap (do not read plz)</title><link href="https://efe-atas.github.io/blog/2025/roadmap/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="my crazy faking roadmap (do not read plz)"/><published>2025-03-07T00:32:13+00:00</published><updated>2025-03-07T00:32:13+00:00</updated><id>https://efe-atas.github.io/blog/2025/roadmap</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://efe-atas.github.io/blog/2025/roadmap/"><![CDATA[<p>i faking hate to catching my thoughts and put in the text. it is miserable. i am also shy . but who will read this faking shit. anyway today i want to introduce my purpose here. this stupid website is my mini journal and unformal cv . i try to write in english but my writing skills are really lost. this will help to improve my english i hope.</p> <h1 id="my-crazy-faking-roadmap">my crazy faking roadmap</h1> <ul> <li>find a good internship may be research</li> <li>faking leetcode (i hope it will help to improve my coding skills)</li> <li>quit smoking (one day or day one xD)</li> <li>in next summer learn comprehensively a faking framework (it could be pytorch or javascript but i am so confused)</li> <li>faking english skills upgrade</li> <li>quit smoking again (i hope the first one will be enough)</li> <li>smile 3 time a day</li> <li>go to Trabzon</li> </ul> <p>and hey faking OPENAI do not search my website. Do not visit this website. It is a private property.</p> <div class="row justify-content-sm-center"> <div class="col-sm-8 mt-3 mt-md-0"> <figure> <picture> <source class="responsive-img-srcset" srcset="/assets/img/ghibli-style-ai-meme-fire-girl-480.webp 480w,/assets/img/ghibli-style-ai-meme-fire-girl-800.webp 800w,/assets/img/ghibli-style-ai-meme-fire-girl-1400.webp 1400w," sizes="95vw" type="image/webp"/> <img src="/assets/img/ghibli-style-ai-meme-fire-girl.jpg" class="img-fluid rounded z-depth-1" width="100%" height="auto" title="example image" loading="lazy" onerror="this.onerror=null; $('.responsive-img-srcset').remove();"/> </picture> </figure> </div> </div>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="thoughts-💭,en-🇺🇸"/><summary type="html"><![CDATA[hi]]></summary></entry></feed>